<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Some monitoring guys</title><link>/</link><description></description><atom:link href="/feeds/tevin-joseph-k-o.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 10:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>Can India retain world cup?</title><link>/can-india-retain-world-cup/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Of course, India have the ability to retain the world cup. The key players will be Kohli, Raina, Bhuveneswar Kumar and captain Dhoni himself. If Kohli is in full flow, no opposition can stop him. What is the specialty of this young champion player is, if he gets to good start, he makes sure he will be there at the end of the innings. The ability to score centuries at ease make him one of the best in the world. Then comes Suresh Raina, he is a complete package for every captain. Brilliant fielder, Good batsman and partnership breaker too. If he gets a chance to bat NO.4 for above, he will win a lot of matches for you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="enter image description here" src="http://s3.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/ms-dhoni-suresh-raina-virat-kohli-and-bhuvneshwar-kumar.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all know the finishing talent of Dhoni. He finishes things in style. His captaincy and keeping the wickets will be key for India. On his day, no one can compete with Rohit Sharma. He has got some serious talent. If he can iron out his laziness, as kohli said earlier he will be X-factor for India in the world cup. Dhawan has  some problems against short pitch deliveries, but he too can play a major role. Rahane/Rayidu will provide stability in the middle order. The likes of Aswin, Jadeja/Akshar patel can bat too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only one of Aswin, Jadeja/Akshar patel will play in world cup because the pitches support more bounce.  Akshar will be the first choice because of his recent success. Bhuvi and Umesh Yadav will be key for India in bowling. Bhuvi can swing bowl in both ways while Umesh bowls in express pace. Varun Aron also can add variety too the Indian attack. Let's not forget Shami who is the highest wicket taker for India in recent times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, with Raina, Kohli, Jadeja and Rahane India is world class fielding unit and this makes India a balanced side. The bouncy pitches are a bit of concern  but, believe me, this guys won't disappoint you.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tevin Joseph K O</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:,2015-01-02:can-india-retain-world-cup/</guid><category>Pujara</category><category>Kohli</category><category>Raina</category><category>Dhoni</category><category>Bhuveneswar Kumar</category><category>Rohit Sharma</category><category>Rahane</category><category>Shikhar Dhawan</category><category>Jadeja</category><category>Aswin</category><category>Akshar Patel</category><category>Shami</category><category>Varun Aron</category></item><item><title>Sydney Test - Make or break for Pujara</title><link>/sydney-test-make-or-break-for-pujara/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Sydney test will be in the headlines for many reasons, first test of Virat Kohli as India's full time skipper, Saha looks to step into the shoes of Dhoni as keeper. However, the test will be important for another individual who is none other than India's NO.3 &lt;a href="http://www.espncricinfo.com/india/content/player/32540.html"&gt;Cheteshwar Pujara&lt;/a&gt;. Pujara is the most talked and technically sound batsmen of current Indian team. What is so special about this young man? He has the ability to play long innings. When he hits hundred, he  makes sure it's big. He has scored 6 hundreds till date and four of them are 150+ scores with two double hundreds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="enter image description here" src="http://s.ndtvimg.com/images/content/2014/jul/806/pujara-out-sad.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pujara has an exceptional average of 75 in home tests. Even though, his career average still looks really good (47.11) he averages only 28.35 in away tests. Have a look at his averages in last 3 series'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Newzeland&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mf"&gt;15.00&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;England&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mf"&gt;22.20&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Austraila&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;on&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;going&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;series&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;):&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mf"&gt;33.50&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Things are not looking nice for India's No.3 who once compared with Rahul Dravid. His back foot play was found wanting of late. Clearly he struggled. Almost every game he got starts, but failed to convert all those. He scored only 2 fifties in the last 3 series'. He played county cricket for regainig form after the poor show in England but, unfortunately he hasn't played a defining Pujara innings yet in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May be he is one big innings away from regaining his touch. People like &lt;a href="http://www.espncricinfo.com/india/content/player/290716.html"&gt;Kedar Jadhav&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.espncricinfo.com/india/content/player/422108.html"&gt;KL Rahul&lt;/a&gt; are pushing their cases to selectors. So, Sydney test will be make or break for Pujara. If he gets a good knock he will stay else he will found himself out of the test squad.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tevin Joseph K O</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:,2015-01-01:sydney-test-make-or-break-for-pujara/</guid><category>Pujara</category><category>Kohli</category><category>Dhoni</category><category>Saha</category><category>Kedar Jadhav</category><category>KL Rahul</category><category>Sydney Test</category></item><item><title>Can Suresh Raina change India's overseas conundrum?</title><link>/can-suresh-raina-change-indias-overseas-conundrum/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Suresh Raina raises his bat when he hits century on debut" src="http://p.imgci.com/db/PICTURES/CMS/134800/134878.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's almost certain that &lt;a href="http://www.espncricinfo.com/india/content/player/33335.html"&gt;Suresh Raina&lt;/a&gt; will play 3rd test against Australia in Melbourne. Rohit Sharma will be on the sidelines since he couldn't do justice to his talent. Raina is regarded as one of the best ODI and t20 players that India has ever produced, but he couldn't replicate his form in tests.  Has Raina wasted so many opportunities? He averages a poor 28.44 in tests. He was dropped after his miserable performances in England, Dravid was the only batsmen who tasted success in the series(Virat and Pujara also failed 2014 England series). Raina was scape goat because selectors has to drop someone after the 4-0 series, Raina was the lone junior batsmen so he was dropped. He was the 2nd highest run getter for India against West Indies which concluded just before the England series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2014 England series was the same overseas story for India, though India managed to win the Lord's test(Lost 3-1). Indian team was really down after the poor test series. All Indian's thought that India would fail in ODI series too. But Raina had other plans, he turned the tables with a brilliant 74 ball &lt;a href="http://www.bcci.tv/news/2014/features-and-interviews/8615/when-it-raina-ed-in-cardiff"&gt;hundred&lt;/a&gt; in Cardiff. India won the ODI series thanks to the enormous energy Raina brought into the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, India is struggling against Australia (Australia lead the 4 test match series, 2-0). India have other problems like &lt;a href="http://www.hindustantimes.com/sports-news/cricketnews/india-vs-australia-behind-unrest-after-brisbane-test-a-kohli-dhawan-spat/article1-1299351.aspx"&gt;Virat-Dhawan spat&lt;/a&gt;. So, Indian need to prove the world that they still have some fight left. I believe Raina can provide the much needed momentum with his willow and his brilliant fielding. One of the main reasons that India failed in tests, is that India's poor slip fielding. Raina is an excellent slip fielder.So, he can resolve issues in slips. Raina can also help MSD with his part time bowling too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, Raina's problems against short pitched bowling are well documented. Raina has done a lot of hard work to iron out his flaws, recent series' show that the hard work has paid of. Every Indian cricket fan wants India to win the Melbourne test, hope Raina can swing the momentum back to India's favour.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tevin Joseph K O</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2014 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:,2014-12-25:can-suresh-raina-change-indias-overseas-conundrum/</guid><category>Suresh Raina</category><category>IndiaVsAustralia</category><category>Melbourne Test</category></item><item><title>Become a successful software developer</title><link>/become-a-successful-software-developer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Success is what everyone wants. It can only be achieved through sheer hard work. How can you become a successful software developer?  Well, it is not that hard. Practising a few small things can do wonders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solve problems&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try to solve maximum problems. You can find a lot of resources in Internet. For example, you can find python practice book here. Remember, practice makes man perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simple Hello,world!&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you start to study/implement something, first you have to make sure  simple things work properly. Always go for ‘Hello,world!’ first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write simple, readable code:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing bunches of code does not make you a good programmer, write code as simple as possible. It should be readable and self explanatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal projects&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do some personal projects. Implementing a project will increase your confidence level up to a great extent. You may come across some difficulties, but in the end you will be a happy person. It helps you to identify your strengths and weaknesses. It would be nice if you can reverse engineer some of the projects you like. Push your work on  &lt;a href="http://github.com/"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;. So that, you can show others what you have done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Googling:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to become the best in the industry? The only shortcut is, to become a good googler. Googling is an art. You might have noticed that an experienced developer gets solutions easily while googling than a less experienced developer. It will also be more accurate. That is, googling skill improves through experience. If you are a newbie, don’t worry there are some tips and tricks to improve your googling skill. Here is an &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/websearch/answer/134479?hl=en"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; which can help you to be a good googler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communication plays a key role in becoming a successful professional. Efficient communication increases productivity. When you are starting to do a task, make sure that you are clear on it. Discuss with your seniors and team lead to get a more clearer picture. When you discuss with others, you will get more points on the topic and get feedback of your approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blogging:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogging is another way to improve your knowledge. By blogging, you can share your ideas and knowledge. Writing a blog in a topic which you are comfortable, will make you thorough with it. It also improves your language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read Tech news:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should be technically updated. You can achieve this trait by  reading some of these sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://slashdot.org"&gt;Slashdot&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com"&gt;Arstechnica&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com"&gt;Mashable&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="htttp://gizmodo.com"&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com"&gt;Techcrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Active in forums:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be active in forums and discussions. It will improve your knowledge and make you sharper. &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com"&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; is a good one to start with.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tevin Joseph K O</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>tag:,2014-09-15:become-a-successful-software-developer/</guid><category>programming</category><category>software development</category></item><item><title>Executing bash commands via python</title><link>/executing-bash-commands-via-python/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In python, executing bash commands can be done using &lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/2/library/subprocess.html"&gt;subprocess &lt;/a&gt; module. It’s pretty easy to use and it’s a powerful module. For simple commands,  we can use &lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/2/library/subprocess.html#subprocess.call"&gt;subprocess.call&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;subprocess&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;subprocess&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;call&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;command1&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;subprocess&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;call&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;command1&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;arg1&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;arg2&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Eg:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;subprocess&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;subprocess&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;call&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;ls&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;-l&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;total&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;rw&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;rw&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;--&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;tevin&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;tevin&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;15&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Sep&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;29&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;test&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;txt&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You can also use &lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/2/library/subprocess.html#subprocess.check_call"&gt;subprocess.check_call&lt;/a&gt;  and &lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/2/library/subprocess.html#subprocess.check_output()"&gt;subprocess.check_output&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Popen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more flexibility, you can use &lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/2/library/subprocess.html#popen-constructor"&gt;Popen&lt;/a&gt; . Using this you can store the output of command as well as any error occurred during command execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eg:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;process = subprocess.Popen([&amp;quot;ls&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;-l&amp;quot;])
(output, err) = process.communicate()
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/2/library/subprocess.html#subprocess.Popen.communicate"&gt;communicate&lt;/a&gt;  method interacts with process and waits for the process to complete. It returns a tuple consisting of stdout and stderr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Executing commands in background:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;subprocess.Popen() only runs a process in the background if nothing in the python script depends on the output of the command being run. For example, the following code won’t be executed in background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;subprocess&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;process&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;subprocess&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Popen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;ls&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;-l&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;stdout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;subprocess&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;PIPE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Thinking about what is subprocess.PIPE?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;subprocess.PIPE: Special value that can be used as the stdin, stdout or stderr argument to Popen and indicates that a pipe to the standard stream should be opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changing directory(cd command):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be thinking that why ‘cd’? Why it can’t be executed using subprocess?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use subprocess.call(“cd ..”), it will throw an error ‘No such file or directory’. It is because cd is a shell internal. So you can only call it as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;subprocess.call(&amp;#39;cd ..&amp;#39;, shell=True)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;But it is pointless to do so.  As no process can change another process’s working directory (again, at least on a UNIX-like OS, but as well on Windows), this call will have the subshell change its dir and exit immediately. Don’t worry you can change directory using os.chdir(path).&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tevin Joseph K O</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>tag:,2014-09-04:executing-bash-commands-via-python/</guid><category>Programming</category><category>Python</category><category>Linux</category><category>bash</category></item><item><title>JSFiddle - Write and share JS easily</title><link>/jsfiddle-write-and-share-js-easily/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is the backbone of front-end developers. In fact, knowledge in JavaScript is an added advantage for every web developer. Need some tool/website for trying out JavaScript? Need a site which can be used for sharing your js code? A site that can be used to edit js code by multiple persons simultaneously? All in one, check out &lt;a href="http://jsfiddle.net"&gt;jsfiddle.net&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can edit your js code and can share the code by a unique URL using jsfiddle. On the left side of the site, you can select the library you want to use and there are separate boxes for editing HTML, CSS and JS. Here is an example fiddle using jQuery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://jsfiddle.net/fxoc1a20/"&gt;jsfiddle.net/fxoc1a20/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using collaboration, you can invite multiple persons to edit your code. Moreover, the site has support for almost all front-end libraries/frameworks. It supports jQuery, Dojo, ember.js, angular js, underscore.js, Extjs, prototype.js and a lot more. Give it a try, I’m sure, jsfiddle won’t disappoint you. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tevin Joseph K O</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>tag:,2014-08-01:jsfiddle-write-and-share-js-easily/</guid><category>Programming</category><category>Javascript</category><category>jQuery</category></item><item><title>Come and get inspired :)</title><link>/come-and-get-inspired/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you want to accomplish something, you need inspiration. Inspiration may come in the form of books, people, incidents etc. Certainly words of legends will help. All legends were winners one way or other way. “Winners don’t do different things, they do things differently”.
Here are some inspirational quotes of some computer tech giants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linus Torvalds (Founder of linux):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most good programmers do programming not because they expect to get paid or get adulation by the public, but because it is fun to program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richard Stallman(Father of Free Software/Open Source):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to accomplish something in the world, idealism is not enough – you need to choose a method that works to achieve the goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bill Gates(Founder of Microsoft):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s fine to celebrate success but it is more important to heed the lessons of failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steve Jobs (Founder of Apple):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your time is limited, so don’t waste it living someone else’s life. Don’t be trapped by dogma – which is living with the results of other people’s thinking. Don’t let the noise of others’ opinions drown out your own inner voice. And most important, have the courage to follow your heart and intuition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Larry Page(Co-founder of Google):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we were motivated by money, we would have sold the company a long time ago and ended up on a beach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Courtesy: &lt;a href="http://www.brainyquote.com/"&gt;http://www.brainyquote.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tevin Joseph K O</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>tag:,2014-05-09:come-and-get-inspired/</guid><category>googling</category><category>software development</category></item><item><title>Googling tips</title><link>/googling-tips/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Google is part of everyone’s life.  Especially people who are working in software industry, google is inevitable. If you can search google effectively, you can become a king in software industry. So, here are some tips and tricks that make your life easier :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;define : If you want to get the definition of a word use ‘define’
   keyword.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eg: define  awesome&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time: Get the time of a location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eg: time ottawa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;weather: Get the weather of a location&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eg: weather ottawa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calculations: Do your mathematical calculations in the search box&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eg: sin(ln(sqrt(31E4)))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“search_term”: If you want to get the occurrence of the exact term, use "search_term".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eg: "India"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-search_term : Used for excluding a word. This is especially useful for words with multiple meanings, like Jaguar the car brand and
   jaguar the animal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eg: jaguar speed -car&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;filetype: Used for filtering your results with given file type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eg: If you are searching for css tutorial and you only need ppt files. Then, search css tutorial filetype:ppt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;site: Search within a site or domain. It used when you want to get
   results from a particular site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eg: If you want to get results only from stackoverflow.com, search python comprehension site:stackoverflow.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;related: Search for pages that are related to the given url.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eg: You know &lt;a href="www.facebook.com"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; is a social networking site and you want to know what are the other social networking sites. Search related:facebook.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;info: Get information of site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eg: If you want get information about a site, say, &lt;a href="twitter.com"&gt;twitter.com&lt;/a&gt; search info: twitter.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;conversions: For unit conversions use in or to operator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eg: 1 pound in kg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy googling :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, go to &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/websearch/answer/134479?hl=en"&gt;https://support.google.com/websearch/answer/134479?hl=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tevin Joseph K O</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>tag:,2014-05-09:googling-tips/</guid><category>googling</category><category>software development</category></item></channel></rss>